Assistant to the President, Office of the; Records ua000.005
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
Office of the Assistant to the President Records
1949-1974
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
State University of New York at Albany
ua000.005
11.16 cubic ft.
This collection contains materials related to administration of the University at Albany and was created by the Assistant to the President.
Administrative History
The Office of the Assistant to the President has been a dynamic role in the University Administration. They have worked performing day to day clerical work, corresponding with other institutions and sometimes acting in the president's stead.
Scope and Contents
This collection is made up of materials collected by the Office of the Assistant to the President. They include budgets requests for the university, correspondence with university employees as well as other institutions, and other general administrative materials.
Acquisition Information
Materials were given to the University at Albany from the Office of the Assistant to the President at an unknown date.
Arrangement of the Collection
Collection is organized in five different series covering various assistants as well as general administrative documents.
Access
Access to this group is unrestricted.
Administrative records.; School budgets; Administrative assistants; UAlbany Presidential Offices; Universities and colleges--Administration
- Budget Requests, 1961-1971; 1; 1.0 cubic ft. (Box 1)
  Arrangement
  Series is arranged in original order.
  Scope and Contents
  Series is made up of various collected budget requests submitted to the main SUNY Administrative offices. They contain plans for the completion of various apsects of the campus during its inital constuction in the late 1960s and early 1970s.
  - Middle States Association Evaluation, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Justification for Proposed Henry Hudson Planetarium, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Supplementary Report to the National Council for Accreditation of Teacher Education, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Hudson Planetarium Prospectus, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Instructional Resources Center Budget Estimate Justification with Draft, 1967-1970 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Preliminary Capital Construction Budget Request, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Short Range Enrollment Goals for 1970-1971, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Facilities Project Justifications Budget Request, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - A Study of the Food Service, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - A Study of the Bookstore, 1971 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Degree and Other Formal Programs Currently Offered in SUNY System, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - University Senate Rough Draft of Minutes and Bills, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Interim Revision to 1968 Master Plan, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - State University of New York Development Document, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Suggested Administrative Organization for SUNY Albany, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Budget Supplementals, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Administrative Salaries, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Program for Henry Hudson Planetarium, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - National Science Foundation Curriculum Evaluation Package I (1of 2), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - National Science Foundation Curriculum Evaluation Package I (2 of 2), 1969 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - National Science Foundation Curriculum Evaluation Package II, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - National Science Foundation Curriculum Evaluation Package III, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - "The Academy in Turmoil" First Report of the Temporary Commission to Study the Causes of Campus Unrest, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 23)
- Records of Clara Maidenbaum, 1968 October 25-1971 June 1; 2; 0.33 cubic ft. (Box 2)
  Series is made up of correspondence and requests from Clara Maidenbaum's work as Assistant to the Vice President.
  - Report of the Task Force on the Academic Calendar, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Tenure Committee Reports, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Center for Science and Society, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Radical Student Leader, Appearance at SUNY A, 1968 November (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Taylor Laws, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Records of Edward Jennings, 1959-1970; 3; 2.50 cubic ft. (Box 1, Box 2, Box 3, Box 4)
  Series is arranged in its original order.
  Thsi series is made up of materials transferred by Theodore Jennings. It contains files from the Office of the Assistant to the President including correspondence with other institutions, adminstrative documents, as well as documents from various events the President attended.
  - Chancellor's Panel On University Purposes, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minutes of the Chancellor's Student Cabinet, 1970 March 12-1970 March 13; 1970 April 24 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Plant Department Memos, 1964-1971 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - The Chancellor's Report to the President vol. 1 no. 1- vol 1 no. 4, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Selected Activities at SUNYA, 1964 November-1964 December (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Selected Activities at SUNYA, 1965 January 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Selected Activities at SUNYA, 1966 January-1966 December (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Monthly Report on Activities for the Newsletter, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Assistantships/ Fellowships assigned to the University, 1965-1970 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - School of Business Supplement to Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - School of Criminal Justice Dean's report, 1968-1970 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - College of Arts and Sciences Annual Report, Division and Department Head Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - School of Education, Annual Report, Department Head Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - College of General Studies, Annual Report, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - School of Library Science, Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - School of Nursing, Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Graduate School of Public Affairs, Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - School of Social Welfare, Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Office of Graduate Studies, Annual Reports, 1968-1969; 1969-1970; 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Graduate Academic Council, Annual Reports, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Placement Service, Annual Report, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Office of the Vice President for Research, 1971 June (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Report of the President, 1969-1970; 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Request and Guidelines for the Annual Report from the President's Office, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - President's Annual Report, Draft Material, 1969-1970; 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Presidential Budget Message Material, 1970 July 7 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Environmental File Sub- file Benjamin Franklin College, 1970 October-1970 November (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Environmental Studies, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - SunyA- Student Association Central Council Preliminary Prospectus 2: The Development of a New Community, 1970 November (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - Myren Richard, Dean School of Criminal Justice, 1964-1972 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Selected Activities at SUNYA, 1969-1971 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Project Themis and Dog Grants, 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - New York State Teachers Association, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Nominations for National Awards, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - National Science Foundation, 1966-1970 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges, 1962-1966; 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - School of Nursing, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Madrid Program, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Luchins, Abraham, 1964-1967; 1970 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Joint Office of Institutional Research for Your Information, 1959-1963 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Job Openings at SUNYA, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Inauguration Invitations to President Collins at College and Universities, 1969-1970 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Interact, Communities with SUNY Students, 1970 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - International Fire Administration Institute, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - SUNYA Budget, 1963; 1966-1971 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Faculty Information Coffee Hour, 1966-1970 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - International Visitors, 1967-1968 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Tyler Ralph, Visit to SUNYA, 1968 February 28-1968 April 29 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Middle States Visitation (1 of 3), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Middle States Visitation (2 of 3), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Middle States Visitation (3 of 3), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - University Goals, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Universities Fall and Spring, 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - New Patterns of Undergraduate Education Fall, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Torch Night Procedure, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Trustees Conference, 1968 February 6 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Trustee Conference, 1968 February 14 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Summer Programs, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - ECS, Education Commission of the States, 1970 January-1970 December; 1971 January (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Short Responses in Education, School of Education, SUNYA vol. 4 no. 3, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - ETS Development, 1962 September; 1964 May; 1965 February (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Dr. Paul Boomsliter, Chairman, Department of Speech Pathology and Audiology, 1963; 1970 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Collective Bargaining, Undated (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Faculty Senate Bulletin and Membership, 1966-1970; 1968-1969 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Congressional Correspondence, 1969-1971 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - University Governance, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Printing Requests Central Stories Requisition, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Institute on Math and Science, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Conference on Science and Religion, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 25)
  - Communications, 1990 (Box 2, Folder 26)
  - Higher Education Conference, 1968 March 3 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  - Faculty Coffee Hours, 1968 (Box 2, Folder 28)
  - Equal Employment at SUNYA, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 29)
  - Graduate Academic Council (1 of 3), 1970 (Box 2, Folder 30)
  - Graduate Academic Council (2 of 3), Undated (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Graduate Academic Council (3 of 3), Undated (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Hearing Committee, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Grapevine, Department of Educational Administration, 1969 June-1969 November (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Sept '66, 1966 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Sept '65, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Convocation, Commencement, 1965-1966 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Correspondence to and from SUNYA, 1969-1970 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Environmental Problems, 1970 (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - School of Library Science, 1963-1964 (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - School of Business, 1964-1967 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Records of James M. Lewis, 1949-1971; 4; 1.33 cubic ft. (Box 1, Box 2)
  This series is made up of documents collected and created by James M. Lewis, Assistant to the President of the Univerisity. Items in the series include correspondecne, profiles on faculty, plans for university initiatives, and invitations for the President to other University functions.
  - Academic Freedom, 1961 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Administrative Data Processing Review Board, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - American Studies Proposal - Art Collins (english professor), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Apthec Rev Problem, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Schaefer, Vincent (Atmospheric Science Research Center), 1962-1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - By- Laws Question, 1953; 1964; 1965 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Classical Association of the Empire State, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Minutes - Collge of General Studies Meeting, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General Studies - Music, 1970-1971 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - College of General Studies - Non-credit program, 1976 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Collins, Evan, 1963-1968 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Collins, Evan R. Folder 2, 1949-1965 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Committee on Speakers and Performers, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Comments on the ASP, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Committee on Student Publications, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Cooperating Center Newspaper, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Correspondence Between SUNYA President Collins and Senators Ja Uits and Kennedy, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hemenway, Curtis (Budley Observations), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Papers on Ecology, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Education, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Faculty Rights (campus political activities), 1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Federal Programs Meeeting, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Corbrey, Malcolm (food service), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Free Speech on Campus, 1962; 1968 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Finta, Mamfer, 1966-1969 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - Historical Information Survey, 1936; 1943; 1962; 1967 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Instrumental Center (Mrs. Cadbury), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - Isreal Project File, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Leese, Joesph (Kettering Proposal), 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - King, Martin Luther, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - Faculty Handbook Review Committee, 1967-1968 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - Lake George Project (atmospheric science), 1967-1969 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - Building Plans, 1960-1963 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Campus Minstery, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Edsall, naima (asst. Dean of women), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Digest of Master Plan, 1962 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1965; 1969 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Newspaper Clippings, 1949-1970 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Publications, Articles, 1969 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Center for Economic Education, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Patent Policy, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Peace Proposal - Correspondence, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Planetarium Memos, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Popularizing SUNYA, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - Center for Advanced Studies in Human Population, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - Publicity - New Campus, 1964-1965 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - Review, Robert (National Conseurancy), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Rudrick, Albert, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Summer Offerings, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Schodak, Boning, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - St. Mary's Park - Albany High School, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - SUNY Expansion, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Rice, Richardson Jr. - School of Social Welfare, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - SUNYA- Faculty/Staff Info (General), 1971 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Audio + Video / Radio + TV, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Rennesalaerele Institute (October Seminar), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Institute of Man and Science - Ford Foundation, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Institute of Man and Science - Man + Machines Seminar, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Institute of Man and Sciene - Correspondence, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 58)
  - Institute on Man and Sciences (Martin Brooks), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 59)
  - Institute of Man and Science - Seminar on Change, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 60)
  - Institutes on Man and Sciences - Broad Resolution, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 61)
  - Institute of Man and Science - Related Correspondence, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 62)
  - Institute of Man and Science - Papers on Cognition, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 63)
  - Institute of Man and Science - Collins, Evans, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 64)
  - Institute of Man and Science - SUNYA and Institute Affiliations, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 65)
  - Invitations, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Invitations, 1961-1966 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Invitation File (No representation), 1961-1969 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Legislative, New York, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Office of the President, 1970 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - President, Benezet, 1969-1975 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - President, Kuusisto, 1969-1970 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - New York State Council of the Arts, 1963-1966 (Box 2, Folder 8)
- Administrative Records, 1951-1974; 5; 7.0 cubic ft.
  Series ia arranged in its original order.
  Series is made up of basic administrative records from the Assistant to the President. Items include correspondence, meeting minutes, documents on University protocol, Radio and television programs from local stations, and information on faculty.
  - Administrative Data - Processing Review Board, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Admissions, 1961-1966 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - "The Colonial News" - SUNY-B Paper Student Government, 1968 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Bomb Threats - Policy and Procedures, 1965-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Correspondence - General, 1966-1968 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Draft Statement for Lyndon B. Johnson, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Eastern Science Congress, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Emeritus Committee, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Oswego Conference - 1964 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Flinton, Edgar W. - School of Graduate Studies, 1962-1965 (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - French Cultural Exchange, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - G.E. College Bowl, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Gifts to University, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Gould Reports, 1967-1971 (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Governor's Budget Recommendation, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Grant, Mort - Israel Affiars, 1960-1964 (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Honors Convocation, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Hughes, Mrs. Marian I. - Associate Education Exchange (State Education Dept.), 1966-1967 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Hussain, Sadiq - West Pakistan, 1962-1967 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Immigration - Petition to Classify Status of Alien (Dept. of Justice), 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - Institute of Internation Education, 1964-1964 (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - Langmuir-Whitney (Distinguished Scientist Program - Proposal), 1966 (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - Lee, Harry O., 1966 (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - Speech after death of John F. Kennedy, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - Money Behind our Colleges (Moonshooter), 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - NATO Briefing Team, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - Empie, Paul (Chairman Zoning Appeal Board Town of Guilderland, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - New Campus Clippings, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - Building Names, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 29)
  - New Campus Plans, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 30)
  - New England Board of Higher Education, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 31)
  - New Paltz Branch of School of Library Science, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 32)
  - "Newmanite" - Newman Association, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 33)
  - Student Announcements (General), 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 34)
  - Student Association, 1962-1963 (Box 1, Folder 35)
  - Campus Chest, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 36)
  - Student Press Conference Notes, 1967 (Box 1, Folder 37)
  - Student Science Journal, 1965-1966 (Box 1, Folder 38)
  - Summer Programs, 1966 (Box 1, Folder 39)
  - Summer Program, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 40)
  - Summer Programs, 1964 (Box 1, Folder 41)
  - Tapes on File, 1963-1967 (Box 1, Folder 42)
  - Trustee Conference, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 43)
  - New York State Teachers Retirement System, 1963-1966 (Box 1, Folder 44)
  - New York Teachers Association, 1962-1970 (Box 1, Folder 45)
  - New York State Health Insurance + Life Insurance (facts), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 46)
  - Nuclear Accelerator (Proposal), 1965 (Box 1, Folder 47)
  - Peace Corps, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 48)
  - Perlmutter, O.W. Dr., 1963-1965 (Box 1, Folder 49)
  - Placement, 1960-1966 (Box 1, Folder 50)
  - Programs and Courses, 1964-1967 (Box 1, Folder 51)
  - Proposal for Major in Language + Area Studies, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 52)
  - Proposal for Degree Program in Geology and Atmospheric Sciences, 1963 (Box 1, Folder 53)
  - Proposed Requirement - Bachelor of Fine Arts Degree, 1963-1964 (Box 1, Folder 54)
  - Recruitment Material, 1962-1966 (Box 1, Folder 55)
  - Regents Advisory Committee on Education Leadership, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 56)
  - Regional Accreditation - AAUP, 1965 (Box 1, Folder 57)
  - Revisions- Summary Bills Red book, Legisalation Manual, 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Research Foundation, 1961-1967 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Reilly, Edwin, 1964-1966 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Salaries, 1958-1967 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - J. Woodrow Sayre (Center for Economic Education), 1965-1967 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Correspondence- Material on "Seminar on Change", 1965 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Speakers on Campus, 1962-1966 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Specifications Survey for New Campus Needs, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Staff Prospects, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - School of Social Welfare, 1963 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Selective Service, 1966 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Seminar on Change, 1965 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Inaguration- State University of New York, 1965-1969 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Music Department - Performances, Concerts, 1964-1967 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - State Univeristy of New York, 1962-1970 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Student Housing, 1962-1965 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Symposium "America at Mid-Century", 1964-1965 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - University Seal, 1963-1964 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Data Book and Higher Education Enrollment, 1960-1964 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Visitors '67, 1967 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Physical Education Department - (DR Alfred Werner), 1963-1965 (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Whittock, Donald, 1963-1967 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - U.N. Seminar on Peaceful Change., 1966 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Academic Teacher Certification Project, 1959-1960 (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Accrediting Agemcy Middle States Association, 1952-1961 (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Annual Reports, Master Plan, 1970-1973 (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Black Unrest, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Board of Regents, 1960-1967 (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Boilers, Reports from Department of Labor, 1950-1954 (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - DeMarco Ruling and Claims, 1947-1949 (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Boy Scouts of America, 1952 (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Compliance Review, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Herman Cooper, 1949 (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Deanship, 1951-1952 (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Divison of Teacher Education, 1953 (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - EOP, ca.1969 (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Faculty, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Faculty Inpact for new Dean, 1951 (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Faculty Senate, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 16)
  - Fraternities and Sorities, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 17)
  - Gelbond, Ainard, 1950-1955 (Box 3, Folder 18)
  - Graduate School Of Public Affairs, 1965-1969 (Box 3, Folder 19)
  - History of College, 1950; 1952; 1964 (Box 3, Folder 20)
  - History of SUNYA, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Inauguration of Emmett B. Fields, 1975 (Box 3, Folder 22)
  - Kirkpatrick, John (Report on slow learner and academically handicapped), 1959 (Box 3, Folder 23)
  - Kuusisto, Dr. Allan A., 1970 (Box 3, Folder 24)
  - Master Plan (Nelson Associates), 1963-1966 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - McInty-Wilson-Robinson Laundry, 1965 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Mendus, Edward J., 1963 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Middle States Association, 1942-1951 (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Middle States Committee Chairman, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Middle States Part A(1-34), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Middle States Part B(35-94), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Middle States- First Draft (Question by Question), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Middle States Accreditation, 1960-1966 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Middle States- Annual Report on new Activities, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Middle States Education, 1958-1961 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Middle States- Self Evaluation Report, 1960 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Evaluation for Visiting Team, 1961 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Middle State Evaluation, 1956-1960 (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Middle School Admissions Policy, 1965-1967 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Report to the Commission on Institutions of Higher Education, 1964 (Box 3, Folder 40)
  - Self-Evaluation Report (Final Edited Version), 1960 (Box 3, Folder 41)
  - Scholarship, 1968-1970 (Box 3, Folder 42)
  - Student Unrest, 1970 (Box 3, Folder 43)
  - School of Social Welfare, 1963-1974 (Box 3, Folder 44)
  - State Education Department, 1964-1967 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  - Tuition and Fees, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 46)
  - University Affairs, memo and Reports, 1967-1970 (Box 3, Folder 47)